Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950] PN6110 .P3
Lilly Library
- Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950]
  - Gilbert, William Schwenck, 1838-1911., 5 envelopes (Box 3, Item 33)
    - The Aesthete. "If you're anxious for to shine in the high aesthetic line, as a man of culture rare" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - "As some day it may happen that a victim must be found" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - Bab Ballad. (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - "Conceive me, if you can" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - Ellen M'Jones Aberdeen. "MacPhairson Clonglocketty Angus M'Clain" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - The Englishman. "He is an Englishman!" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - The First Lord's Song. "When I was a lad I served a term" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 1)
    - "The flowers that bloom in the spring, Tra la" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - "For I'm called Little Buttercup – dear Little Buttercup" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - "Gentle Jame was as good as gold" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - H.M. Home Rule Corps. "I am the captain of this Home Rule Corps!" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - "I am the very pattern of a modern major-general" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - "I once was a very abandoned person—" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - "Ida was a twelve month old" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - "If you give me your attention, I will tell you what I am!" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - The Heavy Dragoon. "If you want a receipt for that popular mystery" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 2)
    - The Heavy Dragoon. "If you want a receipt for that popular mystery" (cont.) (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - King Borria Bungalee Boo. "King Borria Bungalee Boo Was a man-eating African swell;" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "Kind Captain, I've important information" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - The Lord Chancellor's Song. "The law is the true embodiment" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "Loudly let the trumpet bray!" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - The Magnet and the Churn. "A magnet hung in a hardware shop" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "A many years ago, when I was young and charming" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "My eyes are fully open to my awful situation-" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "Oh, foolish fay, Think you, because" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "Oh, why am I moody and sad? Can't guess!" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - Pirate King. "Oh, better far to live and die" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - The Policeman's Lot. "When a felon's not engaged in his employment" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 3)
    - "Politics we bar, They are not our bent;" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - "Prithee, pretty maiden-prithee, tell me true" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - Said I to Myself, Said I. "When I went to the Bar as a very young man" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - Sing for the Garish Eye. "Sing for the garish eye" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - Sir Guy the Crusader. "Sir Guy was a doughty crusader" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - The Suicide's Grave. "On a tree by the river a little tomtit" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - "There is beauty in the bellow of the blast" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - "They intend to send a wire To the moon;" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - "Three little maids from school are we" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - "Time was when Love and I were well acquainted." (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - To the Terrestrial Globe. "Roll on, thou ball, roll on!" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - Trio in "Patience". "It's clear that Mediaeval art alone retains its zest" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - "Were I thy bride, Then the whole world beside" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 4)
    - When I First Put This Uniform On. "When I first put this uniform on" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 5)
    - "When I, good friends, was called to the Bar" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 5)
    - The Yarn of the "Nancy Bell". "'Twas on the shores that round our coast" (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 5)
    - Parodies in the style of Gilbert, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 33, Envelope 5)
  - Giles Scroggins Courted Molly Brown., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 34)
    - "Giles Scroggins courted Molly Brown" (Box 3, Item 34)
  - Gilmore, Patrick S., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 35)
    - When Johnny Comes Marching Home. "When Johnny comes marching home again" (Box 3, Item 35)
  - The Gipsy King., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 36)
    - "'Tis I am the Gipsy King" (Box 3, Item 36)
  - The Girl I Left Behind Me., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 37)
    - "The dames of France are fond and free," Anonymous. (Box 3, Item 37)
  - Glover, Richard, 1712-1785., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 38)
    - Admiral Hosier's Ghost. "As near Porto-Bello lying" (Box 3, Item 38)
  - Goldsmith, Oliver, 1728-1774., 2 envelopes (Box 3, Item 39)
    - A description of an Author's Bedchamber. "Where the Red Lion flaring o'er the way" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - The Deserted Village. "Sweet Auburn! loveliest village of the plain" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - The Double Transformation. "Secluded from domestic strife" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - Elegy on the Death of a Mad Dog. "Good people all, of every sort" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - An Elegy on that Glory of Her Sex, Mrs. Mary Blaize. "Good people all, with one accord" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - The Hermit! "Turn, gentle Hermit of the dale" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - Retaliation. "Of old, when Scarron his companions invited" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - Stanzas on Woman. "When lovely Woman stoops to folly" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 1)
    - Stanzas on Woman. "When lovely Woman stoops to folly," (cont.) (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 2)
    - The Traveller. "Remote, unfriended, melancholy, slow" (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 2)
    - Parodies in the style of Goldsmith, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 39, Envelope 2)
  - Good-Bye., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 40)
    - "Falling leave and fading tree," Anonymous. (Box 3, Item 40)
  - Gordon, Adam Lindsay, 1833-1870., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 41)
    - Parodies in the style of Gordon, source poems unknown. (Box 3, Item 41)
    - The Sick Stockrider. "Hold hard, Ned! Lift me down once more, and lay me in the shade." (Box 3, Item 41)
  - Graham, Harry, 1874-., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 42)
    - Parodies in the style of Graham, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 42)
  - Graham, James., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 43)
    - If Doughty Deeds my Lady Please. "If doughty deeds my lady please" (Box 3, Item 43)
  - Graves, Alfred Perceval, 1846-1931., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 44)
    - Father O'Flynn. "Of Priests we can offer a charmin' variety" (Box 3, Item 44)
  - Graves, John Woodstock, 1795-1886., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 45)
    - D'ye Ken John Peel? "D'ye ken John Peel with his cost so gay?" (Box 3, Item 45)
  - Graves, Robert, 1895-., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 46)
    - Parodies in the style of Graves, source poems unidentified. (Box 3, Item 46)
  - Gray, Thomas, 1716-1771., 5 envelopes (Box 3, Item 47)
    - The Bard. "Ruin seize thee, ruthless King!" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - The Descent of Odin. "Uprose the king of men with speed" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Elegy. Written in a Country Churchyard. "The curfew tolls the knell of parting day" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 1)
    - Elegy. Written in a Country Churchyard. "The curfew tolls the knell of parting day," (cont.) (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Elegy. Written in a Country Churchyard. "The curfew tolls the knell of parting day," (cont.) (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Elegy. Written in a Country Churchyard. "The curfew tolls the knell of parting day," (cont.) (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Hymn to Adversity. "Daughter of Jove, relentless power" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Ode on a Distant Prospect of Eton College. "Ye distant spire, ye antique towers" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - Ode on the Spring. "Lo! where the rosy-bosom'd Hours" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - On the Death of a Favorite Cat. "'Twas on a lofty vase's side" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
    - The Progress of Poesy. "Awake, Aeolian lyre, awake" (Box 3, Item 47, Envelope 2)
  - Greene, Albert G., 1802-1868., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 48)
    - The Baron's Last Banquet. "O'er a low couch the setting sun" (Box 3, Item 48)
    - Old Grimes. "Old Grimes is dead; that good old man" (Box 3, Item 48)
  - The Gunpowder Plot., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 49)
    - "I sing a doleful tragedy,-" (Box 3, Item 49)
  - Hankin, St. John, 1869-1909., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 50)
    - De Gustibus. "I am an unadventurous man" (Box 3, Item 50)
    - General (Box 3, Item 50)
  - Harvey, Frederick William, 1888-., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 51)
    - General (Box 3, Item 51)
  - Harvey, T.K., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 52)
    - General (Box 3, Item 52)
  - Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 53)
    - General (Box 3, Item 53)
    - Satires of Circumstance. "Why do I keep it? That is what you'd ask! (Box 3, Item 53)
  - Harte, Bret, 1836-1902., 2 envelopes (Box 3, Item 54)
    - The Aged Stranger. "'I was with Grant- 'the stranger said" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - Dickens in Camp. "Above the pines the moon was slowly drifting" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - Further Language from Truthful James. "Do I sleep? do I dream?" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - General (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - Jim. "Say there! P'r'aps" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - Plain Language from Truthful James. "Which I wish to remark,-" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - Plain language from truthful James (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 1)
    - Plain language from truthful James, cont. (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 2)
    - The Return of Belisarius. "So you're back from your travels, old fellow" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 2)
    - The society upon the Stanislaus. "I reside upon Table Mountain, and my name is Truthful James;" (Box 3, Item 54, Envelope 2)
  - Hawker, Robert Stephen, 1803-1875., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 55)
    - Song of the Western Men. "A good sword and a trusty hand!" (Box 3, Item 55)
  - Hay, John, 1835-1905., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 56)
    - General (Box 3, Item 56)
    - Jim Bludso. "Wall, no! I can't tell where he lives" (Box 3, Item 56)
    - The mystery of Gilgal. "The darkest, strangest mystery" (Box 3, Item 56)
  - Heber, Reginald, 1783-1826., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 57)
    - Missionary Hymn. "From Greenland's icy mountains" (Box 3, Item 57)
  - Hemans, Felicia Dorothea, 1793-1835., 2 envelopes (Box 3, Item 58)
    - The Better Land. "'Ihear thee speak of the better land;" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 1)
    - Casabianca. "The boy stood on the burning deck" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 1)
    - The Graves of a Household. "They grew in beauty side by side" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 1)
    - He never smiled again. "The bark that held a prince went down" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 1)
    - The Homes of England. "The stately Homes of England!" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 1)
    - The Homes of England. "The stately Homes of England!", cont. (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 2)
    - The Hour of Death. "Leaves have their time to fall" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 2)
    - The Landing of the Pilgrim Fathers. "The breaking waves dashed high" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 2)
    - The Messenger Bird. "Thou art come from the spirits' land, thou bird!" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 2)
    - The Traveler at the Source of the Nile. "In sunset's light, o'er Afric thrown" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 2)
    - The Treasures of the Deep. "What hidest thou in thy treasure caves and cells" (Box 3, Item 58, Envelope 2)
  - Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 59)
    - Ballad Made in the Hot Weather. "Fountains that frisk, and sprinkle" (Box 3, Item 59)
    - Ballade of Midsummer Day and Night. "With a ripple of leaves and a tinkle of streams" (Box 3, Item 59)
    - General (Box 3, Item 59)
    - Invictus. "Out of the night that covers me" (Box 3, Item 59)
    - London Voluntaries. "Down through the ancient Strand" (Box 3, Item 59)
    - Nocturn. "At the barren heart of midnight" (Box 3, Item 59)
    - To W.A. "Or ever the knightly years were gone" (Box 3, Item 59)
    - What is to come. "What is to come we know not. But we know" (Box 3, Item 59)
  - Herford, Oliver, 1863-1935., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 60)
    - The Yak. "This is the Yak, so neg-li-gee;" (Box 3, Item 60)
  - Herrick, Robert, 1591-1674., 2 envelopes (Box 3, Item 61)
    - Cherry Ripe. "Cherry ripe, ripe, I cry" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - General (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - An Ode for Ben Jonson. "Ah Ben!" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - The Poetry of Dress. "A sweet disorder in the dress" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - To Anthea Who May Command Him Any Thing. "Bid me to live, and I will live" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - To Daffodils. "Fair Daffodils, we weep to see" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - To Virgins, to Make Much of Time. "Gather ye rosebuds while ye may" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
    - Whenas in Silk my Julia Goes. "Whenas in silks my Julia goes" (Box 3, Item 61, Envelope 2)
  - Hill Lady Arthur., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 62)
    - In the Gloaming. "In the gloaming, oh, my darling" (Box 3, Item 62)
  - Hoare, Prince, 1755-1834., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 63)
    - The Arethusa. "Come, all ye jolly sailors bold" (Box 3, Item 63)
  - Hodgson, Ralph, 1871-1962., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 64)
    - General (Box 3, Item 64)
  - Hogg, James, 1770-1835., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 65)
    - The Gude Greye Katt. "There wase ane katt, and ane gude greye katt" (Box 3, Item 65)
    - Kilmeny. "Bonnie Kilmeny gaed up the glen;" (Box 3, Item 65)
    - The Skylark. "Bird of the wilderness" (Box 3, Item 65)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 66)
    - The Chambered Nautilus. "This is the ship of pearl, which, poets feign" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - Contentment. "Little I ask; my wants are few;" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - The Last Leaf. "I saw him once before" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - The One-Hoss Shay. "Have you heard of the wonderful one-hoss shay" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - The Problem. "I like a church; I like a cowl;" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - Stanzas. "Strange! That one lightly whispered tone" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - The Treadmill Song. "The stars are rolling in the sky" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - The Voiceless. "We count the broken lyres that rest" (Box 3, Item 66)
    - Parodies in the style of Holmes, original poem unidentified. (Box 3, Item 66)
  - Home, John, 1722-1808., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 67)
    - Norval. "My name is Norval: on the Grampian hills" (Box 3, Item 67)
  - Hood, Thomas, 1799-1845., 4 envelopes (Box 3, Item 68)
    - The Bridge of Sighs. "One more Unfortunate" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 1)
    - Domestic Asides; or, Truth in Parentheses. "'I really take it very kind,'" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 1)
    - The Dream of Eugene Aram. "'Twas in the prime of summer time" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 1)
    - Faithless Sally Brown. "Young Ben he was a nice young man" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 1)
    - General (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 1)
    - The Haunted House. "Some dreams we have are nothing else but dreams" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 2)
    - Hymn to the Sun. "Giver of glowing light!" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 2)
    - I remember, I remember. "I remember, I remember" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 2)
    - Miss Kilmansegg and Her Precious Leg. "To trace the Kilmansegg pedigree" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 3)
    - No! "No sun – no moon! (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 3)
    - The Song of the Shirt. "With fingers weary and worn" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 3)
    - The Song of the Shirt, cont. "With fingers weary and worn" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 4)
    - To a False Friend. "Our hands have met, but not our hearts;" (Box 3, Item 68, Envelope 4)
  - Hook, Theodore Edward, 1788-1841., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 69)
    - Parody in the style of Hook, original poem unidentified. (Box 3, Item 69)
  - Hopkinson, Joseph., 1 envelope (Box 3, Item 70)
    - Hail, Columbia! "Hail, Columbia! 'happy land!" (Box 3, Item 70)
  - The House that Jack Built., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 1)
    - "This is the house that Jack built." Annonymous (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Housman, Alfred Edward, 1859-1936., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 2)
    - "When smoke stood up from Ludlow" (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Howe, Julia (Ward), 1819-1910., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 3)
    - Parody in the style of Howe, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Howitt, Mary (Botham), 1799-1888., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 4)
    - The Spider and the Fly: An Apologue. '"Will you walk into my parlor?' said the Spider to the Fly. (Box 4, Item 4)
  - The Hunt is Up., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 5)
    - The hunt is up, the hunt is up" (Box 4, Item 5)
  - Hunt, Josephine., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 6)
    - You Kissed Me. "You kissed me! My forehead drooped low on your breast" (Box 4, Item 6)
  - Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 7)
    - Abou Ben Adhem. "Abou Ben Adhem (may his tribe increase!)" (Box 4, Item 7)
    - Rondeau. "Jenny kissed me when we met" (Box 4, Item 7)
  - Hunter, Mrs. John., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 8)
    - The Village seems asleep while Lubin is away. "My mother bids me bind my hair" (Box 4, Item 8)
  - Huxley, Aldous Leonard, 1894-1963., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 9)
    - Parody in the style of Huxley, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 9)
  - I'm Afloat! I'm Afloat!, 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 10)
    - "I'm afloat! I'm afloat! on the fierce rolling tide--" (Box 4, Item 10)
  - Ingelow, Jean, 1820-1897., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 11)
    - Divided. "An empty sky, a world of heather" (Box 4, Item 11)
    - Feathers and Moss. "The marten flew to the finch's nest" (Box 4, Item 11)
    - The Letter L. "We sat on grassy slopes that meet" (Box 4, Item 11)
  - Ingram, John Kellis., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 12)
    - The Memory of the Dead. "Who fears to speak of Ninety-Eighty?" (Box 4, Item 12)
  - Ireland, William Henry, 1777-1835., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 13)
    - The Mistress's Question. "Where dwells the rosy-dimpled boy?" (Box 4, Item 13)
  - Jefferys, Charles., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 14)
    - Jeannette and Jeannot. "You are going far away, far away from poor Jeannette" (Box 4, Item 14)
    - Mary of Argyll. "I have heard the mavis singing" (Box 4, Item 14)
  - John Brown's Body., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 15)
    - John Brown's body lies a mould'ring in the grave" (Box 4, Item 15)
  - Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 16)
    - "How rarely reason guides the stubborn choice" (Box 4, Item 16)
    - Imitation of the Style of ***(Warton). "Hermit hoar, in solemn cell" (Box 4, Item 16)
    - "When Learning's triumph o'er her barboarous foes" (Box 4, Item 16)
  - Jones, Sir William, 1746-1794., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 17)
    - An Ode in Imitation of Alcaeus. "What constitutes a state?" (Box 4, Item 17)
  - Jonson, Ben, 1573-1637., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 18)
    - "Have you seen but a bright Lily grow" (Box 4, Item 18)
    - Hymn to Diana. "Queen and huntress, chaste and fair" (Box 4, Item 18)
    - It is not Growing Like a Tree. "It is not growing like a tree" (Box 4, Item 18)
    - Ode on the Stage. "Come, leave the loathed stage" (Box 4, Item 18)
    - Song. "Still to be neat, still to be drest" (Box 4, Item 18)
    - To Celia. "Drink to me only with thine eyes" (Box 4, Item 18)
    - The Triumph of Charis. "See the chariot at hand here of Love!" (Box 4, Item 18)
  - Ka-Foozie-Um., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 19)
    - "In ancient days there liv'd a Turk" (Box 4, Item 19)
  - Keats, John, 1795-1821., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 20)
    - La Belle Dame sans Merci. "O what can ail thee, knight-at-arms" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - Breathe softly, flutes. "Be tender of your strings, ye soothing lutes;" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - The Dove. "I had a dove, and the sweet dove died;" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - From the Song of the Indian Maid. "Beneath my palm-trees, by the river side" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - The Human Season. "Four seasons fill the measure of the year;" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - Happy Insensibility. "In a drear-nighted December" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - Ode on a Grecian Urn. "Thou still unravished bride of quietness!" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - Ode to a Nightingale. "My heart aches, and a drowsy numbness pains" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - On First Looking into Chapman's Homer. "Much have I travelled in the realms of gold" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - A thing of beauty is a joy for ever:" (Box 4, Item 20)
    - Parody in the style of Keats, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 20)
  - Kendall, May., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 21)
    - Ship of Dreams. "When silent lies the sleeping town" (Box 4, Item 21)
  - Kendall, Henry., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 22)
    - Astarte. "Across the dripping ridges" (Box 4, Item 22)
  - Kenney, James, 1780-1849., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 23)
    - Said a Smile to a Tear. "Said a Smile to a Tear" (Box 4, Item 23)
  - Keppel, Caroline., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 24)
    - Robin Adair. "What's this dull town to me?" (Box 4, Item 24)
  - Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item Item)
    - The Star-Spangled Banner. "Oh, say can you see by the dawn's early light" (Box 4, Item Item)
  - The King of the Cannibal Islands., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 26)
    - "Oh! have you heard the news of late" (Box 4, Item 26)
  - Kingsley, Charles, 1819-1875., 3 envelopes (Box 4, Item 27)
    - Airly Beacon. "Airly Beacon, Airly Beacon;" (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 1)
    - "I once had a sweet little doll dears" (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 1)
    - O Mary, Go and Call the Cattle Home! "O Mary, go and call the cattle home" (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 1)
    - Ode to the North-East Wind. "Welcome, wild North-easter!" (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 1)
    - The Outbit. "It was an hairy oubit, so proud he crept along;" (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 1)
    - The Three Fishers. "Three fishers went sailing away to the west" (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 1)
    - The Three Fishers. "Three fishers went sailing away to the west," (cont) (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 2)
    - Parodies in the style of Kingsley, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 27, Envelope 3)
  - Kinney, Coates, 1826-1904., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 28)
    - Rain on the Roof. "When the humid shadows hover" (Box 4, Item 28)
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936., 9 envelopes (Box 4, Item 29)
    - The Absent-Minded Beggar. "When you've shouted 'Rule Britannia,' when you've sung 'God save the Queen" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Back to the Army Again. "I'm 'ere in a ticky ulster an' a broken billycock 'at" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - The Ballad of East and West. "Oh, East is East, and West is West, and never the twain shall meet" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - The Betrothed. "Open the old cigar-box, get me a Cuba stout" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Bobs. "There's a little red-faced man" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Cells. "I've a head like a concertina, I've a tongue like a button-stick" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Certain Maxims of Hafiz. "If it be pleasant to look on, stall in the packed serai" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Chant-Pagan. (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - The Conundrum of the Workshops. "When the flush of a new-born sun fell first on Eden's green and gold" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Danny Deever. "What are the bugles blowin' for?' said Files-on-Parade." (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 1)
    - Danny Deever. "What are the bugles blowin' for?' said Files-on-Parade." (cont.) (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 2)
    - The English Flag. "Winds of the World, give answer?" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 2)
    - L'Envoi. "When Earth's last picture is painted, and the tubes are twisted and dried" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 2)
    - L'Envoi. "When Earth's last picture is painted, and the tubes are twisted and dried," (cont.) (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 3)